Alice Chambers

Central Quay, 33 Alma Street, Kellam Island, Sheffield 07971395264

Alicee5cha@gmail.com

Personal Profile

I am currently a first year student at Sheffield Hallam University, studying software engineering. I would like to gain more work/practical experience, so I can put the skills that I have learnt into practice. I have worked in the design/tech sector for 4 years before starting university as this sector is something, I have always had a passion for.

Key Skills

- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Photoshop/Illustrator.
- Published articles on the Madlab website and Bipolar UK.
 https://madlab.org.uk/2016/05/manchester-bipolar-youth-support-group/
- Created multiple WordPress websites with HTML/CSS/Java/PHP. www.mede-care.co.uk
- Adaptable and quick to learn new skills.
- Confident in communicating with a wide range of people.
- Proficient in programming C++ and C#

Employment History

MED e-care June 2016 – June 2018

Digital Marketing Apprentice – (became Manager of the Marketing Dept. for UK after first year)

MED e-care are a SaaS business who provide care records and medication records for Care Homes and Pharmacies in the UK, America and Canada.

- I developed and created two WordPress websites using HTML/CSS/Java/PHP, one of which is the main website for potential UK clients. See www.mede-care.co.uk.
- I have created numerous leaflets and brochures to use as marketing and sales materials using Photoshop/Illustrator.
- I developed an announcement page using HTML, CSS and Java to help new users get to grips with the software.
- I have solely organised the trade shows in Birmingham and London.
- Created an advertisement video using Adobe Animate CC and Character Animator CC.
- Managed Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn accounts and scheduled posts
- I helped to prepare the business for the new GDPR laws put in place in 2018, so I have made sure all my marketing strategies are in line with the new regulations.
- After developing the new website, I also ran a launch campaign for it and optimised it for search engines, and we now appear on the first page of google.

Madlab - *Digital Assistant*April 2016 – June 2016

Manchester Digital Laboratory (MadLab) is a well-known and innovative organisation, based in Northern Quarter. Their primary areas of focus are science and technology; arts and culture.

- Building the social media presence of Madlab via a number of online platforms, with sole responsibility for Instagram. During my time at Madlab I have actively increased traffic to all social media outlets.
- Involved in the advertising of upcoming events and groups.

- Photography and photo editing.
- Designed merchandise to improve brand awareness.

42nd Street, Great Ancoats Street - Peer Ambassador

Dec 2015 - Present

As a 42nd Street Peer Ambassador my role includes meeting regularly with key staff to design and deliver projects that will benefit young people in the local community that have experienced well-being or mental health difficulties.

Duties:

- Listening to and capturing the views and experiences of other young people and using this to influence the development of services.
- Building a movement of young people that can influence local, regional and national policy and practice.
- Organising and speaking at events including colleges, schools and an AYPH conference.
- Involved in media projects to raise awareness.
- Helping to run campaigns e.g. attitude and behaviour change campaigns, awareness raising campaigns as well as fundraising projects.
- Taken and edited photos to put on the charities social media page

Education

BTEC – Creative Media Production Distinction*
 FCSE French Distinction
 11 GCSE's A*-C

HND Level 4 Digital Marketing
 Pass (This is a pass or fail qualification)

Software Engineering Beng – modules for first year Component Programming, Maths for SE, Fundamentals of programming, Systems modelling, professional project development, Fundamentals of Computer Architecture (2018 - current)

Hobbies & Interests

- Heavily involved in charities and projects.
- I enjoy playing computer games and rock climbing.
- I am creative which is why I enjoy drawing, sewing and the creative side of IT and media, including film-making, photo editing and animation which are all areas I work to improve on in my spare time. in my spare time.
- I like to keep up-to-date with social networking platforms.
- I particularly enjoy coding and developing websites, as well as learning and reading about new technology.

References available upon request.